<recipe
  title="Dosa"
  pre-prep-time="12-14 hours"
  prep-time="1 hour"
  cook-time="5 minutes per dosa"
  serves="12-14 dosas"
>
  <inspiration
    text="Classic Masala Dosa - NY Times"
    url="https://drive.google.com/open?id=1dKKyunkmldu0tDLFNJ-tlPwkgdQDStvz"
  />

  <image url="dosa.jpg" />

  <ingredients title="Dosa Batter">
    2 cups short-grain rice
    ½ cup urad dal (split husked black lentils)
    1 tsp fenugreek seeds
    ½ tsp salt
    Vegetable oil, for frying
  </ingredients>
  <ingredients title="Potato Filling">
    3 tbsp vegetable oil
    1 tsp mustard seeds
    ½ tsp cumin seeds
    1 medium onion, diced
    1 red pepper, chopped into 1cm pieces
    ½ tsp salt
    ½ tsp turmeric
    Pinch asafetida
    1 tbsp grated ginger
    6-8 curry leaves
    4 garlic cloves, minced
    6 small-medium potatoes, boiled, peeled and cubed
    3 small sweet potatoes, boiled, peeled and cubed
  </ingredients>
  <method>
    <step>
      <i>Make dosa batter</i>: rinse rice in a bowl, then cover with 4 cups cold
      water. Rinse urad dal and fenugreek seeds in a small bowl, then add
      cold water to cover. <b>Leave both to soak for 4-6 hours</b>.
    </step>
    <step>
      Separately drain rice and dal-fenugreek mixtures. Put rice in food
      processor, add 1 cup cold water, grind to smooth paste (may have to
      work in batches). Repeat with the dal-fenugreek mixture.
    </step>
    <step>
      Combine both pastes in a medium mixing bowl. Whisk together, adding
      enough water to obtain a medium-thick batter. Cover bowl with kitchen
      towel and set in a warm place. Let ferment until the surface is
      bubbly, <b>about 8 hours</b>. Stir in the salt. Use batter straight away or
      refrigerate for later use (batter will keep for up to a week
      refrigerated. Thin with water if necessary before proceeding).
    </step>
    <step>
      <i>Make potato filling</i>: Parboil the potatoes
    </step>
    <step>
      Put oil in wide skillet over medium heat. When oil is wavy, add cumin
      and mustard seeds. Wait for seeds to pop, about 1 min, then add red
      pepper and onion. Stir until onions have softened, about 5 min. Season
      lightly with salt. Add turmeric, asafetida, ginger, curry leaves, and
      garlic. Sit to coat and let sizzle for 1 min.
    </step>
    <step>
      Add potatoes and ½ cup water. Cook, stirring well to combine, until
      liquid has evaporated ~5min. Mash potatoes a bit with the back of a
      wooden spoon. Season well with salt, then set aside at room temperature
      (potato filling can be prepared a day in advance)
    </step>
    <step>
      <i>Make dosa</i>: set cast-iron skillet over medium heat. Brush with vegetable
      oil/butter. Ladle ¼ cup batter in the centre of the skillet, and using
      bottom of ladle, quickly spread batter outwards in circular motion to a
      diameter of ~7inches. Drizzle ½ tsp oil over the top. Leave dosa batter
      to brown gradually until outer edges begin to look dry ~2min, cooking
      one side only. Spoon ½ cup potato filling on top of dosa in the centre
      as a strip and fold dosa to make cylindrical shape. Serve immediately.
      Continue making dosa one at a time.
    </step>
  </method>
</recipe>
