<recipe
  title="Mushroom &amp; Leek Stroganof"
  prep-time="10 minutes"
  cook-time="25 minutes"
  serves="2"
>
  <inspiration
    text="Mushroom Leek Stroganoff recipe by Nisha Vora"
    url="https://thefeedfeed.com/rainbowplantlife/mushroom-leek-stroganoff"
  />

  <ingredients>
    2 tbsp olive oil, divided into 1 tbsp each
    2 leeks, cleaned, trimmed, sliced
    4 cloves garlic, minced
    350g mushrooms, sliced
    1 tsp dried thyme
    1 tsp salt, divided and more to season
    375mL vegetable broth
    2 tbsp soy sauce
    1 tbsp vegan Worcestershire sauce (optional)
    30g all purpose flour (or 2tbsp cornstarch)
    ½ cup dry white wine (pinot grigio or sauvignon blanc)
    400mL full fat coconut milk
    2 tbsp tahini
    2 tbsp nutritional yeast
    1 tsp paprika
    ½ tsp dijon mustard
    We served with pan fried crisp kale
  </ingredients>
  <method>
    <step>
      Heat 1 tbsp olive oil in a large pot over medium high heat. Once oil is
      shimmering, add leeks and saute for 2-3 minutes, stirring occasionally, until
      lightly brown.
    </step>
    <step>
      Add the remaining 1 tbsp olive oil, along with garlic, mushrooms, and thyme.
      Stir to combine. Saute for 4-5 min or until mushrooms are lightly browned and
      tender. Add ½ tsp salt and cook for one more minute
    </step>
    <step>
      While mushrooms are cooking, mix vegetable broth, soy sauce, worcestershire
      sauce (optional), and flour (or cornstarch) in a measuring cup or bowl, whisking
      to combine
    </step>
    <step>
      Pour the vegetable broth-flour mixture into the pot and whisk to combine,
      ensuring there are no flour clumps. Bring to a simmer.
    </step>
    <step>
      Pour in the white wine with the cooked mushrooms and allow to simmer for 3 min
      or until the smell of alcohol has dissipated.
    </step>
    <step>
      Pour in coconut milk, tahini, nutritional yeast, the remaining ½ tsp salt, and
      paprika. Bring to simmer over medium-low heat. Cook for 10 minutes until the
      sauce is thickened and very creamy.
    </step>
    <step>
      Stir in dijon mustard and taste for seasonings, adding more salt if needed.
      Garnish with parsley and vegan parmesan if desired.
    </step>
  </method>
</recipe>
