<recipe
  title="Mushroom and Ale Pie"
  prep-time="20 minutes"
  cook-time="1-2 hours"
  serves="2"
>
  <inspiration
    text="Mushroom and Ale Pie - BBC Food"
    url="https://www.bbc.co.uk/food/recipes/mushroom_ale_pie_90722"
  />

  <image url="mushroom-and-ale-pie.jpg" />

  <ingredients url="Filling">
      15g dried mixed mushrooms
      250mL just-boiled water
      4 tbsp sunflower oil
      300g shallots, peeled and cut in half if large
      1 medium onion, thinly sliced
      2 garlic cloves, crushed
      400g mixed mushrooms (chestnut, button, shiitake, portabello, quartered or sliced if large)
      330mL pale ale (vegan)
      1 vegetable stock cube
      2 tbsp tomato purée
      2 tbsp redcurrant jelly
      1 tbsp soft light brown sugar
      1 tbsp fresh thyme leaves or 1 tsp dried thyme
      2 bay leaves
      3 tbsp cornflour mixed with 3 tbsp cold water
      180g cooked and peeled chestnuts
      flaked sea salt and ground black pepper
  </ingredients>
  <ingredients url="Vegan Pastry">
    300g plain flour, plus extra for rolling
    1 tsp fine sea salt
    100g sunflower oil
    5-6 tbsp cold water
    1 tbsp aquafaba or plant-based milk
  </ingredients>
  <method>
    <step>
      Rehydrate dried mushrooms
    </step>
    <step>
      Heat 2 tablespoons of oil in a large non-stick frying pan. Fry the
      shallots and onion over a medium heat for 10-12 minutes, or until
      softened and lightly browned, stirring occasionally. Add the garlic
      and cook for a few seconds more. Tip into a bowl and set aside.
    </step>
    <step>
      Heat the remaining oil in the same frying pan and fry the mixed
      mushrooms for 5 minutes, or until lightly browned.
    </step>
    <step>
      Stir in the soaked mushrooms and their liquor, the ale, crumbled stock
      cube, tomato purée, redcurrant jelly, brown sugar, thyme and bay leaves.
      Add the shallots and onions back into the pan. Season with a good pinch
      of salt and lots of ground black pepper.
    </step>
    <step>
      Bring the liquid to a gentle simmer and cook for 15–20 minutes, stirring
      occasionally. Mix the water with the cornflour in a small bowl until
      smooth, and stir into the mushroom mixture. Cook for 1–2 minutes or until
      the sauce thickens, stirring. Stir in the chestnuts and season to taste.
    </step>
    <step>
      Spoon the mushroom mixture into a 1.5 litre/2½ pint pie dish and leave to
      cool before topping with pastry.
    </step>
    <step>
      Preheat the oven to 200C/180C Fan/Gas 6.
    </step>
    <step>
      To make the pastry, mix the flour and salt in a large bowl. Add the
      sunflower oil and rub into the flour first with a fork and then with
      your fingertips until the mixture resembles breadcrumbs. Don’t let the
      mixture come together in a ball, it should remain in damp, flaky pieces.
    </step>
    <step>
      Add the cold water and mix with a fork and then your hands until the
      dough comes together and forms a smooth ball.
    </step>
    <step>
      Dust a work surface with flour. Dust a rolling pin with a little more
      flour, then roll out the dough until around 7.5mm/⅜in thick. Cut a circle
      of pastry that is around 3cm/¼ in larger than the pie dish containing the
      filling. Reserve the trimmings for decoration.
    </step>
    <step>
      Brush the rim of the pie dish with a little aquafaba or plant-based milk
      and place the pastry on top. Press the pastry edges firmly to seal and
      trim off any excess with a knife. Brush the pastry all over with aquafaba
      or milk.
    </step>
    <step>
      Use the trimmings to make decorations for the pie. Brush with more
      aquafaba or milk.
    </step>
    <step>
      Bake the pie for 45–50 minutes, or until the pastry is pale golden brown
      and the filling is hot. Serve with freshly cooked green vegetables and mash.
    </step>
  </method>
</recipe>
