<recipe
  title="Vegan Wellington"
  prep-time="30 minutes"
  cook-time="40 minutes"
  serves="4"
>
  <inspiration
    text="The Ultimate Vegan Wellington"
    url="https://veganhuggs.com/vegan-wellington"
  />
  <image url="vegan-wellington-1.jpg" />
  <image url="vegan-wellington-2.jpg" />
  <image url="vegan-wellington-3.jpg" />
  <ingredients>
    1 sheet vegan puff pastry
    2 tbsp ground flax meal + 5 tbsp water
    2 tbsp cooking oil
    ½ medium onion, diced
    2 small carrots, diced small
    2 stalks celery, diced
    4 cloves garlic, minced or crushed
    1 tsp dried thyme
    1 tsp ground sage
    ½ tsp dried rosemary
    230g mushrooms, finely chopped
    1.5 tbsp tamari sauce (sub soy sauce)
    400g can of chickpeas, drained but not rinsed
    ¾ cup unsalted walnuts, ground into course meal
    ½ cup panko breadcrumbs
    2 tbsp tomato paste
    1½ tbsp vegan worcester sauce
    ½ tsp salt, more to taste
    Fresh cracked pepper, to taste
    1 tbsp vegan butter, melted
  </ingredients>
  <method>
    <step>
      Combine the ground flax and water in a small bowl. Set aside for 10 min.
      It will thicken and gel up
    </step>
    <step>
      Heat oil in a large pan over medium heat. Add onion, celery and carrots.
      Saute until soft ~6-8 min
    </step>
    <step>
      Add garlic, thyme, sage and rosemary. Saute for 1 min
    </step>
    <step>
      Add mushrooms and saute until they soften and release moisture ~5-7 min.
      Add tamari and cook for 1 min. Remove from heat and set aside to cool for
      10 min
    </step>
    <step>
      Add chickpeas to mixing bowl and mash enough to break down whole
      chickpeas, but leave texture
    </step>
    <step>
      Add cooled mixture, chickpeas, breadcrumbs, walnut meal, flax mixture,
      worcester sauce, tomato paste, salt and pepper. Combine well, use hands
      if needed. Add seasonings to taste. (If mixture seems too wet, add
      another ¼ cup of breadcrumbs or rolled oats)
    </step>
    <step>
      Preheat oven to 200oC. Line rimmed baking sheet with parchment paper and
      set aside
    </step>
    <step>
      Using your hands, shape mixture into a solid log that will fit into the
      middle of the pastry sheet (with a few inches of slack). Make sure log is
      packed well.
    </step>
    <step>
      Unroll puff pastry sheet and lay it over the baking tray. Place the loaf
      in the middle of the pastry sheet. Pick up one side and wrap it over the
      loaf and repeat on the other side. Gently press to seal together (don’t
      force if it doesn’t close, just thin and lengthen the loaf or remove some
      mixture and form again) *if pastry doesn’t seal easily, lightly brush a
      little non-dairy milk in that area and seal
    </step>
    <step>
      Roll up the ends and press gently to seal. Trim dough first before
      sealing if there is too much excess dough, otherwise the ends will be
      very doughy. Flip the loaf over so the sealed edges are facing the baking
      sheet
    </step>
    <step>
      Brush the top and side with melted vegan butter. Using a sharp knife,
      gently make diagonal slits across the whole top of the loaf about 1 inch
      apart. Now repeat in the opposite direction to create criss cross slits
    </step>
    <step>
      Place in the oven and bake for 30-35 min until heated throughout and the
      pastry is golden brown. Let sit for 10 min before gently cutting with
      sharp knife (it may be easier to cut along slits that were made earlier).
      Serve with gravy if desired!
    </step>
  </method>
</recipe>
